[Music]
In the previous video, we mentioned
the concept of process or thread,
right?
In this video, I will introduce
you to the thread object, which is
the object through which we
execute our code. In reality,
our code in a real
project will be executed by
threads. I
think today I will discuss
this thread object and
show you how we
understand it. Of course,
for our current demo project,
I believe you
won't see its benefits yet.
Later, when you join
real projects that require a
large number of users
or high performance,
you will definitely need to delve deeper into
this concept. First, let's
look at the documentation for this video.
I've already put it here, and as I
mentioned before, it is...  This
page is called Java concurrency,
and this is in the topic
of how to define a
thread. To define a
thread, there are two ways: you
can inherit an
interface called `runnable`,
or you can
inherit a class. Here,
we'll use the method of inheriting a class.
Our video
is video 61, so today, in
chapter 10, we'll give it a class. Let's call it video 61.
We'll close
everything and inside, we'll give
it a `main` function. Okay, first,
we'll do it simply.
This is `system out`. That's what we'll
do up to this point in video 61.
Right now, we'll
run this `javal application`. Okay, so
here, to implement
a thread, we'll
inherit a class called `runnable`.
Thread, guys. So here, we
'll extend it. We'll
inherit and extend the
thread named. After typing
this, M H doesn't work.
This one seems like we
don't need to import it at all, which is quite unrealistic. We don't need to
import
it. However, if we
don't import it, it's a bit wrong. I
think it's a bit wrong. We
need to override the function called the
run function. We'll override
this run function. In fact, we'll give ourselves
a run function, and now
you'll call it. I'll copy
it directly inside for speed. For example,
I'll call it here. You
give me video 61,
we replace it here. We have a
start function like this. So,
first, we have a file like
this. Let's try running it. Let's see if there are any
problems. In fact,
after you...  It runs like this,
we don't like any difference
except for the log line, right?
But now, try
my code. I've coded it
simply for you. Inside the run function,
copy this block of code
inside the run function.
We'll replace it with the actual
run function.
We'll make it run from here, starting
with 100 billion. Yeah, that's the actual run, right?
I'll use spaces.
Here, it's millions, right? Billions,
so we'll make
it run from 0 to 10
billion, and we'll perform the calculation.
We'll calculate the sum from
0 to 10 billion.
Actually, we're using
a large number so that
our computer takes more
time. So, if you run
it here, you'll get the line called '
start thread,' and then we...  We
call it an end thread if
we've finished the calculation. At the same time, I'll
give it a piece of code like this.
You'll copy the main function exactly.
I'll copy the main function and
throw it down here.
We'll replace it with this (
video 61). We'll replace it here.
Actually, what are we doing
here? Here, we've created a variable `
max`. This `max` variable is actually
a loop.
We'll create as many processes as we
like. For example, here we write
2, meaning we'll loop this
twice, right? If we loop
twice, we'll have two
processes, right? So here, we'll
give it something like this.
First, you'll put it like this. And
here, I'll zoom out a bit.
I'll open this. This time,
I'll open the Performance tab.
Pay attention to the CPU.
My CPU is my computer.
Currently, I'm running...  This is a really powerful CPU,
even more powerful than your computers.
I'm using an i7
12700. Look at this graph.
In reality, my CPU
only used 5 minutes. Now, I'll press the
run button here. You'll see...
I'll drag it a little bit to make it
easier to see. We'll observe it
side-by-side, and then I'll run it.
Notice that
when I press the run button,
my CPU increases.
Look at this graph.
Here I have two graphs. On
this side, I have the start
three threads. This start three threads, and when I
finish, this time it increases to
four. I'll increase it exponentially.
You'll see, I have four
threads. This is
my CPU graph. I'll let it run
again. Look at my CPU;
it increases to 49.  You see? Look
here. You see it's
skyrocketing like this. Just a moment ago it was
around 20. Now it's
increased to 49. Let's put it at 8.
Look at the threads, and
we're going to run this.
You'll see the CPU graph over here. Do
you see anything? Immediately,
our CPU spikes like
this. So, every time
you define an additional processing thread
in your computer, it
consumes your computing resources. More
specifically, for
our addition calculation, our CPU
does that. And later, for example, when
you process a file,
it will definitely consume more
memory. So, in reality,
defining
an
additional
thread means we are processing in parallel, that is,
we are
processing simultaneously.  But there's a
trade-off, which means it will consume
your computer's resources. If your computer is weak,
it's pointless to
run it in multi-threaded mode. Multi-
threading like this is
usually applied to
servers later on, which are usually very powerful to
handle the load and only then does
it become meaningful. Through
this video, I hope you've understood
what threads are. As
for me, I don't want to go into
how to
define a thread, how to
log in, or how to
join a thread. It's meaningless
if you're
working on a project, like
learning Java,
right? I hope that the
knowledge I've introduced
will give you some
understanding of threads.
This is the final video in
our basic Java journey.
In the next video...  In my opinion, I will
guide you through this journey. We will
look back together at what we have been through
and what we will do after
you finish this course.